[Music]
hi everyone and welcome back to the
channel
first off welcome to all the new
subscribers that came from cherry garcia
good to have you on board if you've got
any suggestions for any
new ice creams you want us to make pop
them down in the comments below and
those you that aren't subscribed
hit that button and don't forget to like
all our videos appreciate it thank you
so today's video is a jenny's one
fluffernutter pie what is fluffinutter
it's peanut butter and marshmallow
originally marshmallow fluff hence the
fluff
bit but like most of jenny's there's
some things going on that i just want to
quickly discuss before we get into
making them
there's two halves or two parts there's
two ice creams a marshmallow
ice cream and a peanut butter ice cream
and within both of those
is pie crust it's an oat
based pie crust but what is it and is it
really a pie crust
it's kind of a mix between a crisp
a cobbler a pie crust and a crumble
i want to mix all those words together
you're just going to get some creamble
that's what's going in this essentially
so if you want to see how the
fluffernutter
pie from jenny's is made stick around
and we'll show you
[Music]
the first one we're going to make is the
peanut butter base so pop your
ingredients in a pan
heat that sugar up well and finally add
your peanut butter i'm going to use
skippy here because it's my favorite
now in this ice cream half i'm going to
use a commercial stabilizer and that
needs to be
taken up to a heat of 75 to 80 degrees c
as you can see it's 76.5 77 ish
once it's up to that temperature take it
off the heat pop it in a container and
this is when i'm going to add the cream
bring that temperature down quick and
then you can pop it straight in the
fridge
and the next half of this ice cream is
the marshmallow
so here i'm taking good quality
marshmallows now i've mentioned this
before in a previous video
make sure they taste of something these
ones here have got a really nice strong
vanilla taste
i am going to add a little bit extra
vanilla just to really boost that flavor
but some marshmallows have zero flavor
whatsoever so make sure you choose a
good one
pop your ingredients in the pan add your
marshmallows chopped when you chop them
with a
knife or scissors how i've done or a
spoon if you want to make your life
difficult for yourself
once it's up you can see the
marshmallows will take an absolute age
to melt and then all of a sudden in
about 10 seconds they'll disappear into
your base and you'll be left with a
really nice mix marshmallow's got
gelatin in it
so that will act as a stabilizer for
this half
then pop it into a container add the
cream as normal and then
pop it in the fridge until you're ready
to churn
[Music]
and the final element to this ice cream
the fluffernutter pie
is the crumble crisp
pie crust or whatever you want to call
it
get your ingredients in a bowl blend it
all together
jenny's ice cream when the ingredient
shows she uses sunflower oil i'm not
using sunflower oil i'm using butter
but it doesn't make any difference if
you want to use it's just fat that's
what you need you need a fat to combine
these elements together
once you've mixed it all thoroughly and
there's no lumps left
put it in a pan get it nice and flat and
then pop it in the oven for
15 to 20 minutes once it's suitably
burnt
take it out of the oven and then remove
all those weird burnt bits that you've
just managed to achieve
then when it's cool cut it up into tiny
little sections pop it in a container
put it in the freezer
so as this fluffernutter pie is a
basically a duo
tub we're gonna have to churn if you've
only got one machine
we're gonna churn in two halves so we're
going to churn this first flavor
fill up your container pop some cling
film all over the top
put the lid on and then tap it down for
chef john's style
tap tap tapper and then get it in the
freezer for
20 to 30 minutes that will give you
enough time to clean your machine up and
get your other flavor
in there churning away
so with the tub in your freezer on its
side
get the other flavor churning again this
will take 15 to 30 minutes depending on
your machine
in both of these i've added this crisp
we're going to call it for now
in at the end of the churn my machine's
pretty tough so it can take this
no problem if yours isn't then you might
want to mix this in
in the tub but obviously as a duo type
the second flavor is going to get
difficult
once they're both churned load the
second flavor
into your tub get it tapped down make
sure there's no voids
get the lid on in the freezer give it
three or four hours until we're ready to
eat it
[Music]
just got it out of the freezer look at
that tub design it's great
if you can see that i'll put a close-up
on screen another great tub
my wife does great jobs on these tubs
let's get some scooped out
see what it looks like
[Music]
so
and there we go a nice bit of crisp
actually i'm going to call it a crumble
in this part video a nice bit of crumble
in there
so obviously i've used a smooth peanut
butter you could
technically use any kind of peanut
butter you like but i guess if you use
chunky
whilst you're churning there is the
chance that the peanuts might sink to
the bottom so you might have to turn it
a little bit
harder and then if you've got a weaker
machine it probably would struggle there
hey
experiment see what works for you
marshmallow
i love making marshmallow ice cream it's
got a great taste and texture
it's amazing stuff let's just see what
this is like
[Music]
that's really nice
i put a little bit more salt in this
than
i originally was gonna purely because
peanut butter especially skippy anyways
got quite a lot of sugar in it and
obviously the marshmallows it's quite
high in sugar
so to have that salty crispy crunchy bit
in there
really divides that flavor in two so
when you get a piece of that
crumble keep forgetting what i'm calling
it in there it's a really nice
change in texture and taste that's
really really nice
nice big hit of peanut butter comes
through there skippy it's my favorite
marshmallows a lovely smooth soft
texture
that gelatin really helps to absorb
helps absorb excess
can't talk excess water as well so
all in all this is a really great recipe
but
jenny's it's great ice cream she has a
great
kind of thing going on in the u.s so if
this is something that you want to make
give this a bash i absolutely recommend
it
anyway thanks for joining us on this
what i consider really good
ice cream don't forget to like and
subscribe
any comments or suggestions for future
videos pop them down in the comments
below
and we'll see you next week take care
what else is